<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">TEDxBerkeley</string>
    <string name="hello_world">Hello world!</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="about">About</string>
    <string name="speakers">Speakers</string>
    <string name="schedule">Schedule</string>
    <string name="navigation_icon_description">TEDxBerkeley Logo</string>
    <string name="speaker_photo">Speaker Photo</string>
    <string name="talk_icon">Talk Icon</string>

    <string name="about_ted">
        TED is a nonprofit organization devoted to Ideas Worth Spreading. Started as a four-day conference in California 25 years ago, TED has grown to support those world-changing ideas with multiple initiatives. The annual TED Conference invites the world’s leading thinkers and doers to speak for 18 minutes. Their talks are then made available, free, at TED.com.\n\nTED speakers have included Bill Gates, Al Gore, Jane Goodall, Elizabeth Gilbert, Sir Richard Branson, Nandan Nilekani, Philippe Starck, Ngozi Okonjo-Iweala, Isabel Allende and former UK Prime Minister Gordon Brown. The annual TED Conference takes place each spring in Long Beach, California, along with the TEDActive simulcast in Palm Springs; the annual TEDGlobal conference is held each summer in Edinburgh, Scotland. \n\n

        TED’s media initiatives include TED.com, where new TEDTalks are posted daily, the recently launched TED-Ed platform for students and educators, the Open Translation Project, which provides subtitles and interactive transcripts as well as the ability for any TEDTalk to be translated by volunteers worldwide, and TEDBooks, short e-books by speakers that elaborate on a single idea originally presented on TED’s stage. \n\nTED has established the annual TED Prize, where exceptional individuals with a wish to change the world are given the opportunity to put their wishes into action; TEDx, which offers individuals or groups a way to host local, self-organized events around the world, and the TED Fellows program, helping world-changing innovators from around the globe to become part of the TED community and, with its help, amplify the impact of their remarkable projects and activities.</string>

    <string name="about_tedxberkeley">On February 28, 2015 TEDxBerkeley is gathering world-leading thinkers, makers, and doers at UC Berkeley to discuss “Wisdom.Compassion.Connection.”. The audience will be composed of a diverse mix of over 1800 students, professors, and thought leaders from Berkeley and beyond for a stimulating day of presentations, discussions, entertainment and art that will spark new ideas and opportunities for all. \n</string>

    <string name="lorem_ispum">Bacon ipsum dolor amet pork loin prosciutto flank beef ribs kielbasa tongue. Jerky capicola chuck, corned beef ball tip meatloaf porchetta rump tongue shoulder turkey cow. Tail prosciutto spare ribs pancetta beef ribs, rump sausage landjaeger t-bone ball tip filet mignon meatball bresaola. Hamburger biltong swine cupim meatloaf tongue frankfurter kielbasa chicken. Meatball drumstick biltong salami, shank ball tip kielbasa capicola. Chuck ball tip prosciutto bacon boudin doner capicola landjaeger ham chicken t-bone tongue ribeye turducken alcatra. Shoulder beef ribs fatback cupim pork chop filet mignon bresaola porchetta cow short loin pancetta pig sirloin.

Prosciutto landjaeger spare ribs turkey tenderloin tongue kevin meatball beef ribs shank. Beef pastrami shank meatball doner cupim bresaola ball tip jowl turkey rump strip steak hamburger leberkas ham. Jerky boudin jowl t-bone. Filet mignon venison meatloaf, t-bone shoulder beef ribs tongue doner shank turducken brisket meatball pig. Meatball landjaeger ribeye chicken tenderloin turducken, shankle shoulder.

Filet mignon corned beef tongue short ribs meatball cow tri-tip drumstick pork belly doner beef ribs meatloaf prosciutto. Ham pork chop short ribs tail chuck bresaola. Meatloaf pork sirloin shankle. Bacon brisket shoulder, swine tri-tip picanha prosciutto turkey chuck beef ribs andouille shank filet mignon. Frankfurter turducken shank tri-tip meatloaf kielbasa.

Cupim flank meatloaf tongue boudin filet mignon andouille ground round swine frankfurter sausage. Frankfurter meatball cow picanha landjaeger filet mignon beef ribs salami swine boudin doner brisket. Jowl drumstick beef ribs short loin landjaeger turkey, pastrami beef capicola swine porchetta corned beef t-bone pork belly jerky. Salami corned beef biltong ham.

Strip steak meatball beef ribs bresaola kevin alcatra salami pork picanha. Landjaeger rump flank pork chuck shankle cow meatloaf sausage shoulder short ribs tongue. Tail pork spare ribs sausage cupim tongue drumstick. Brisket porchetta chicken pork belly corned beef chuck doner. Landjaeger tenderloin leberkas andouille, kevin corned beef tongue bacon ham rump turducken tail meatloaf turkey. Cow jerky brisket boudin turkey.</string>

    <string name="ackerman_bio">Suzanne graduated from UCT (University of Cape Town) with a BA in French and Politics. Whilst a student, she was the first woman to chair the University Students Fund raising Rag committee 1984, and was elected vice-chair of SHAWCO.( Students Community Welfare Programs ).  After university, Suzanne received extensive training in supermarkets in France and UK. She settled in France, ran her own businesses in restaurants and nightclubs in a French Ski resort for 7 years. Returning to South Africa, she joined the family Supermarket business, Pick n Pay , as a trainee manager in fresh foods.  During her 19 years in the Company, she worked in various positions in the business, starting from Floor management, and buying, to General Manager of Corporate Affairs and Social Responsibility. In 2007 she founded the Small Business Incubator that seeks to address the social and economic inequalities of the past created by the Apartheid era, by creating access to the formal market for small and previously disadvantaged entrepreneurs. A passionate proponent for equality, job creation and skills development, Suzanne assists many new entrepreneurs in all aspects of business and life skills through a detailed mentorship programme that ensures their sustainability as suppliers to the broader economy.</string>
    <string name="bhangra_bio">Cal Bhangra was formed in 2009 to promote awareness of the Punjabi Culture at UC Berkeley through the performance of Bhangra, a traditional, folk Punjabi dance. Since then, they have competed nationally, year round, hoping to spread Cal pride to all areas of the United States. Their dancers bring high energy, crowd-pleasing routines that aim to entertain crowds of all ages. Their team of passionate Berkeley students aim to teach all audiences the art of Bhangra so that their passion can spread and carry on.</string>
    <string name="gable_bio">As the Founder and CEO of a multi-million dollar 3rd party logistics firm, Carolyn’s road to a successful businesswoman was hardly typical. An average high school student with little motivation and no money to go to college, Carolyn graduated from beauty school to realize she had little interest in the trade. In order to make ends meet, she began waiting tables, a job she held for over a decade. Working in an exclusive restaurant atop of the Hyatt Chicago, wearing the mandatory uniform designed to appeal to the male clientele (including four-inch high heels), she waited on business men and women from all over the country. As a single mother, working for tips and living hand-to-mouth, it was barely enough to cover rent and feed her two kids. Something had to change.\n\n

The change arrived one day when the roof of the restaurant was damaged in a storm, forcing Carolyn to find work quickly. She walked into an employment office and said she wanted a sales job. The counsellor looked at Carolyn, at her previous work experience, and said the best he could do was a Customer Service position at a freight company.\n

Entering the male-dominated freight industry, Carolyn dedicated herself to learning the business and soon found herself in the sales position. A few years later, as the industry became de-regulated, Carolyn recognized an opportunity and started her own business, New Age Transportation, Distribution and Warehousing, Inc.\n\n

As her business flourished, Carolyn never forgot the struggles she endured as a single mother trying to make ends meet as a waitress. With a desire to help ease the financial burdens single, working parents encounter, she created the Expect A Miracle Foundation. The non-profit organization provides assistance for children’s extra-curricular activities – an expense many single parents struggle to afford. Since 2001, the organization has helped nearly 6000 children!\n\n

The dynamic author of Everything I Know as a CEO I Learned as a Waitress, Carolyn outlines her principles for success – which can be applied within business and in one’s personal life. Sharing her life experiences and inspirational thoughts, the confidence her writing instills in the reader to take their own journey is undeniable. Her latest book, The Miracle Path, captures the hope, strength, and courage of others as they continue on their life’s journey. A must-read for anyone that needs a little encouragement in pursuit of a miracle!\n\n

Carolyn generates the spark that you need to believe in yourself and to achieve your goals. She is living proof that individuals can overcome obstacles, beat the odds, and succeed. Hearing her tell her story, her words of inspiration, and her positive approach to the most difficult situations is as insightful to the CEO as it is to the single parent.</string>
    <string name="garcia_bio">Dan Garcia is a Senior Lecturer with Security Of Employment in the EECS Department at the University of California, Berkeley, and joined the faculty in the fall of 2000. Dan received his PhD and MS in Computer Science from UC Berkeley in 2000 and 1995, and dual BS degrees in Computer Science and Electrical Engineering from MIT in 1990. He was chosen as an ACM Distinguished Educator in 2012.\n

He is active participant in SIGCSE (the annual computer science education conference, having presented every year since 2001), and is currently working with the ICSI Teaching Privacy research project. He serves on the ACM Education Board, the Advanced Placement Computer Science Principles Development Committee, is the faculty champion for the local Computer Science Teachers Association chapter, and the faculty co-director for BFOIT, a wonderful Berkeley K-12 outreach effort.\n\n

He is the only person to have won all four of the department’s teaching awards:\n

* the Information Technology Faculty Award for Excellence in Undergraduate Teaching in 2004\n\n
* the Diane S. McEntyre Award for Excellence in Teaching in 2002,\n
* the EECS outstanding graduate student instructor award in 1998, and\n
* the CS outstanding graduate student instructor award in 1992.\n

He was also chosen as a UC Berkeley “Unsung Hero” in 2005. He holds the record for the highest teaching effectiveness ratings (6.7/7) in the history of the department’s lower-division introductory courses.\n\n

He recently co-developed a computing course for non-majors, “CS10: The Beauty and Joy of Computing (BJC)”. This redesign earned a “Bears Breaking Boundaries” curriculum design award, a Lockheed Martin broadening participation grant, and was twice chosen as a national pilot for the new Advanced Placement Computer Science Principles course. In the Spring of 2013, the course had more women than men in it, marking the first time (in campus recorded history) an introductory computing course at UC Berkeley achieved that distinction. Thanks to four NSF grants, they have already offered
professional development to 200 high school teachers across the country, and starting in the summer of 2015, will begin working with 100 more teachers in New York City (his hometown), the largest school district in the country. He is developing a free edX MOOC course based on BJC, to reach even more teachers and students, launching on Labor Day, 2015.
    </string>

    <string name="gopin_bio">Marc Gopin is the Director of the Center for World Religions, Diplomacy and Conflict Resolution (CRDC), the James H. Laue Professor at the School for Conflict Analysis and Resolution at George Mason University, Arlington, Virginia, USA, and co-owner of MEJDI, a peace tourism business that embraces the multiple narratives of indigenous peoples. Gopin has pioneered projects at CRDC in Afghanistan, Iran, Syria, Palestine and Israel.\n\n

Gopin has trained thousands of people worldwide in peacebuilding strategies for complex conflicts. He conducts research on values dilemmas as they apply to international problems of clash of cultures, globalization and development, and social justice. The direction of his new research and teaching investigates the relationship between global trends in nonviolence and new approaches to global conflict resolution.\n\n

Gopin’s fifth book, Bridges Across an Impossible Divide: the Inner Lives of Arab and Jewish Peacemakers (Oxford, 2012), explores the role of self-examination in the resolution of human conflict as portrayed in the lives and testimonies of indigenous peacemakers. Gopin is also the author of To Make The Earth Whole: The Art of Citizen Diplomacy in an Age of Religious Militancy (Rowman and Littlefield Publishers Inc, 2009),Healing the Heart of Conflict, which was published in 2004 by Rodale Press. Holy War, Holy Peace: How Religion Can Bring Peace to the Middle East (Oxford University Press, 2002) was a study on what was missing from the Oslo Process, and what will be necessary culturally for a successful Arab/Israeli peace process, and Between Eden and Armageddon: The Future of World Religions, Violence and Peacemaking (Oxford University Press, 2000), which pioneered the theoretical and practical frameworks for engaging religion in the context of conflict prevention, management and resolution, in addition to numerous chapters in the leading edited volumes of the field of conflict resolution.\n\n

Gopin has engaged in back channel diplomacy with religious, political and military figures on both sides of conflicts. He has appeared on numerous media outlets, including CNN, CNN International, Al Jazeera English, Al Jazeera Arabic, Al Arabiyah, The Jim Lehrer News Hour, National Public Radio, Voice of America, and the national public radios of Sweden and Northern Ireland. He has been published in numerous publications, including the International Herald Tribune, the Boston Globe, the Christian Science Monitor, and his work has been featured in news stories of the Times of London, the Times of India, Associated Press, and Newhouse News Service.\n\n


Dr. Gopin received a Ph.D. in ethics from Brandeis University in 1993.</string>
    <string name="guzman_bio">Described by the New York Times as “an imaginative artist,”  Chilean-born flutist, Viviana Guzmán (www.viviana.org) performs over 50 concerts a year throughout the world. \n Her most recent recording “Traveling Sonata” received a Grammy Nomination.  She has been featured on programs for PBS, NBC, and NPR, seen on the cover of Latina Style Magazine, and in COSMOPOLITAN en Español and has performed in 123 countries, and in all 7 continents including South Africa, Ireland, Spain, Brazil, Bali, India, Peru, Japan, China, Argentina, Greece, often featuring flutes from her collection of over 100 gathered from concert tours.   She has performed as soloist with 65 ensembles including orchestras in Russia,  Chile, Vermont, New York, Wisconsin, California, Texas, Montana, Philippines, in such halls as in Carnegie Hall, Avery Fisher Hall in Lincoln Center, and other prominent stages with such artists as Mikhail Baryshnikov, Placido Domingo, John Denver, and Glenn Close.\n\n Viviana Guzman is the Executive Director of the San Francisco Flute Society and Festival, Flutes by the Sea Masterclasses, and is an Altus Flutes Artist.  Last season included appearances in New Orleans, Honolulu, American Samoa, Mexico, Thailand, Panama, Peru, Chile, and as a soloist with the Philippines Symphony Orchestra in Manila and this season includes performances in Argentina, Philippines, Taiwan, Tahiti, Easter Island, California, and as a soloist with the Southeast Missouri Symphony Orchestra as well as with the San Jose Chamber Orchestra.</string>
    <string name="giminez_bio">Eric Holt-Giménez has been Executive Director of Food First since 2006. He is the editor of the Food First bookFood Movements Unite! Strategies to Transform Our Food Systems; co-author of Food Rebellions! Crisis and the Hunger for Justice with Raj Patel and Annie Shattuck; and author of the book Campesino a Campesino: Voices from Latin America’s Farmer to Farmer Movement for Sustainable Agriculture and of many academic, magazine and news articles. Of Basque and Puerto Rican heritage, Eric grew up milking cows and pitching hay in Point Reyes, CA, where he learned that putting food on the table is hard work. After studying rural education and biology at the University of Oregon and Evergreen State College, he traveled through Mexico and Central America, where he was drawn to the simple life of small-scale farmers.

When he arrived to work in the community of Vicente Guerrero in the impoverished state of Tlaxcala, Mexico in 1977, the place was surrounded by eroded and deforested hills and farmers were not able to grow enough food to feed their families. But the village did have a small elementary school and an energetic young mayor and Eric enthusiastically joined his efforts to revitalize the community. They started a school garden, a water project, a health clinic and a sewing coop. Several Mayan farmers from Guatemala visited at just the right time to lead a field course on soil and water conservation that helped restore the degraded environment and boost farmer’s yields. From that experience, the Campesino a Campesino (farmer to farmer) movement was born. In the four decades since, this peasant-led sustainable agriculture movement has spread steadily across Latin America—creating innovative farming methods, raising yields and improving livelihoods for hundreds of thousands of small farmers and their families.\n\n

After spending over twenty-five years with the resourceful farmers of Central America and Mexico, Eric holds a deep appreciation for the value and power of building local food systems. But he has also become painfully aware that working locally is never going to be enough to bring about the larger changes that are needed: “Small farmers and underserved urban communities need changes in national food policies and international trade rules to have a fighting chance of feeding themselves and building healthy, prosperous livelihoods.”\n\n

Eric has a MSc. in International Agricultural Development from University of California at Davis and a PhD in Environmental Studies from the University of California at Santa Cruz . He has taught Development Studies at UC Berkeley, UC Santa Cruz, Boston University and the National Gastronomic University in Pollenzo, Italy. Prior to working at Food First, he served as the Latin America Program Manager for the Bank Information Center (BIC) in Washington DC.\n\n

In Eric’s words, “successful social movements are formed by integrating activism with livelihoods. These integrated movements create the sustained social pressure that produces political will—the key to changing the financial, governmental and market structures that presently work against sustainability.”</string>
    <string name="joi_bio">Valerie Joi’s song delivery is as fluid and focused as her life. She is a minister extraordinaire and her message of unconditional love and acceptance is clear, strong and uncompromising. Listening to her perform is an artistic and healing journey in itself.\n\n

A gifted and multifaceted musician, Valerie Joi studied classical piano and jazz voice, and has worked with many recording artists as a pianist, vocalist, composer, arranger and producer. She is also a brilliant choir director. She has directed the UC Santa Cruz Gospel Choir for the past eleven years, and was recently named a Porter College Faculty Fellow by the university.\n\n

As the former Music Director for Inner Light Ministries in Santa Cruz, CA, Valerie Joi established a music ministry renowned for its excellence, which culminated in the invitation for the Inner Light Choir to perform on the stage of Carnegie Hall in February 2012, “a clear reflection of their exceptional director” (Dennis Loy, Conductor-inResidence). Valerie Joi received the further honor of singing the solo on her composition “Living Grace” at the Carnegie Hall performance.\n\n

Valerie Joi was featured as one of the Director’s Top Ten Picks at the Monterey Jazz Festival and her music can be heard on the television show In the Light, and in the films Jumpin’ the Broom and God and Gays: Bridging the Gap. With an MBA in Finance and Entrepreneurship from Rice University, Valerie Joi combines her passion for music and education with expertise in business management. To this end, she also works with the Institute for Women’s Leadership promoting gender partnership in the workplace.\n\n

First and foremost, Valerie Joi is a music minister, teaching and preaching music as ministry and connection. Her CD of original compositions, Singing the Sacred Yes, is an invitation to deepen our relationship with the Divine. Her most recent release with the incomparable pianist Tammy Hall, Remembering to Remember: Hymns for the Soul, pays beautiful tribute to the spiritual heritage of our country.\n\n

Valerie Joi is committed to sharing her ministry of love and music with students from all walks of life, as she invites them to bless and be blessed through song. As a consummate expression of music, she uplifts her audiences and inspires them to experience their own sense of Divine Connection.</string>
    <string name="kaipa_bio">Prasad is the CEO of the Kaipa Group in California and is a thought leader in the areas of innovation, leadership development and change management. He is considered to be one of the top management thinkers (#21) of Indian origin by Thinkers50 group. He is the co-author of critically acclaimed and international best-seller (#4 in non-fiction books in India) “From Smart to Wise: Acting and Leading with Wisdom” in 2013. He has been a visiting professor and was the founding Executive Director of the Center for Leadership, Innovation and Change (CLIC) at the Indian School of Business (ISB) and raised multi-million dollar funding for the center. He was also a Smith Richardson Visiting Fellow at Center for Creative Leadership between 2010-11 and was an advisor to Business FAC of Fetzer Institute (2011-13). Prasad taught executive education programs organized by INSEAD, LBS, USC, Dartmouth and IIM Bangalore in addition to ISB.\n\n

Prasad has been an advisor and coach focusing on innovation and leadership since 1990 for about 120 C-level executives in Global Fortune 500 companies. Clients included Adobe, Boeing, Disney, Johnson and Johnson, Maxim and Oracle as well as global/entrepreneurial companies like Aztec, Advanta, BAE Systems, Lunar Design, Mastek, Olixir, Polaris, State Bank of India and Scintera Networks. The purpose of Prasad’s innovation/leadership coaching is to ignite the genius within individuals. Prasad’s unique competence is in helping his clients find their next significant step and take it. He found that unless he helps clients to examine their signature strengths that have turned into “core incompetence” and kept them stuck, it is difficult to ignite and channel their creativity to come up with innovative decisions, products, and services. He assists clients in becoming effective in managing people as well as oneself (personal mastery), getting reenergized and building new capacities, and taking more risks, in addition to innovative and strategic decisions.\n\n

Prasad co-founded the Entrepreneur Institute for TiE in the Silicon Valley in 2002 to assist entrepreneurs develop soft skills and connect, engage and co-create effectively with others in the ecosystem. Over 13,000 entrepreneurs have gone through TiE Institute programs. He is a part-time faculty member at the Saybrook University and works with students in the areas of creativity and innovation, transformational learning and leadership. Prasad is/was on the board of directors/trustees for International Leadership Association (ILA), Marico Innovation Foundation, Samskrita Bharati USA, Integral Leadership Review, Lead India 2020, Society for Organizational Learning (SoL), Aankhen, Mentor Cloud, Intertec Communications, and Hindu University of North America.\n\n

Prasad also worked as an educator/consultant with 100+ companies like Areva, A.P. Moeller Maersk, Canara Bank, Exxon Mobil, Ford, Pepsi (Quaker Oats), Navteq, Nitto-Denko, Sasken, Sun, Syngenta, and Union Bank in the areas of leadership, change management, innovation and management team development. Cisco and HP have worked with Prasad in developing innovative business models for creating a successful new business and in innovating unique, “brandable” product designs that are consistent with their culture.\n\n

As a senior manager in Apple, Prasad was asked to create an educational menu for Apple engineers using innovative learning approaches. In 1999, as a research fellow in the Apple University, and with a charter to help design ‘a learning processor that augments human intelligence,’ Prasad interviewed high achievers and exceptional people researching how they learn (and ‘unlearn’), create, communicate, relate and lead.\n\n

Prasad got his doctorate in physics, and as a professor in the University of Utah helped build an international research laboratory with Dr. Ed Haskell. Athena Interactive released three award winning CD-ROMs for leaders based on his learning interface concepts and his pyramid building (thinking in three dimensions) methodology.\n\n

In addition to ‘From Smart to Wise’ Prasad published an e-book ‘Discontinuous Learning: Igniting Genius Within by Aligning Self, Work, and Family’ and many of his writings and tools are available at http://www.kaipagroup.com. He writes a blog regularly on innovation and leadership in HBR.org and has published articles in Business Week, Forbes, Fortune, and New York Times. He twitter handles are @pkaipa and @fromsmarttowise. Prasad is married to Dr. Vinoda and is father of Pravin (27) and Vidya (23). He enjoys exploring and reinterpreting ancient wisdom (and its application in developing highly effective and authentic leaders), photography , listening to classical music, and playing tennis.\n\n</string>
    <string name="kisyombe_bio">Dr. Victoria Kisyombe is a leader who has used innovation, initiative, and determination to empower women in Tanzania to become economically self-sufficient. Given women’s lack of collateral and resulting lack of access to capital, Victoria began pioneering micro-leasing as a solution. Pioneering micro-leasing model as an alternative way to financing women has generated praise beyond Tanzania, and efforts are under way to expand the model to other countries in the region.\n\n

Victoria has been a true innovator and pioneer in an important area, helping improve the livelihoods of thousands of impoverished women in her country, truly making a world of difference. She was profiled by the World Bank in 2007 – “Doing Business in Africa”.\n\n

The International Alliance for Women honored Victoria in 2009 as WINNER OF THE PRESTIGEOUS TIAW WORLD OF DIFFERENCE 100 AWARDS in the ECONOMIC EMPOWERMENT category. This is in recognition of her outstanding contribution in making “all the difference in the world” to the economic empowerment of women. TIAW is an International umbrella organization based in Canada whose mission is economic empowerment of women entrepreneurs locally, regionally or worldwide.\n\n

World Economic Forum/Schwab Foundation honored Victoria with African Region Award of Social Entrepreneur of the Year 2010 in recognition of visionary, pragmatic and courageous contributions that significantly improve the state of the world. She is now a permanent Schwab Fellow and also a Member of the Global Agenda Council on New Growth Models.\n\n

In 2011, Victoria received an award of “Women of determination 2011” in recognition of her support on development of SMEs in her country during 50 years of independence of Tanzania.\n\n

Hon. Hillary Rodham Clinton honored Victoria with a very prestigious Award on Economic Empowerment in Washington D.C. in recognition of her efforts to empower women in her country and for being a role model and a global leader in the economic empowerment sector. Hon. Hillary Rodham Clinton is the Founder of Vital Voices.\n\n

Victoria Kisyombe is a Pioneer Member of the World Entrepreneurship Forum (Lyon, France); an Associate Member of Women Global Banking Alliance (USA); Eastern and Coastal Diocesan Council Member of the Evangelical Lutheran Church in Tanzania (ELCT); Council Member of United Evangelical Mission (UEM, Germany), Chairperson of UEM’s Foundation Board (Germany), Chairperson of UEM’s Investment Trust; Council Member of Tumaini Makumira University, Chairperson of Coalition of Advancement of Women in Agriculture in Tanzania (CAWAT) which is supported by Land O Lakes, USA.\n\n</string>
    <string name="levin_bio">Emily Levine was a successful television writer/producer (Designing Women, Love and War, Dangerous Minds) as well as a stand-up comedian on TV (“Late Nite with David Letterman”) and at major clubs around the country, but found neither career fulfilling.  Since then, she’s become the Jon Stewart of science, finding comic gold at the interface of science and society.  Her appearances at conferences (including four appearances at TED where she was recently voted one of the 100 all-time favorite speakers); in corporate venues; and onstage (in NY, LA and San Francisco) have received accolades from the press (“One of the new Queens of Comedy”, NEWSWEEK), from the scientific community (“Emily @ the Edge of Chaos” is a brilliant mix of art and science”/BRIAN GREENE and TRACY DAY, co-producers of the World Science Festival); and from her peers (“If you don’t get Emily Levine’s smart comedy, you’re an idiot”/MATT GROENING, creator of “The Simpsons”.)   Emily is in the final stages of post-production on “Emily @ the Edge of Chaos”, a film about how science saved her life and how she will now save the world.</string>
    <string name="rass_bio">Dr. Rasmussen is a medical doctor and the CEO for Infinitum Humanitarian Systems (IHS), an international social business built on a profit-for-purpose model. By training he is an internal medicine physician with both undergraduate and medical degrees from Stanford University and a Masters degree in disaster medicine from the UN World Health Organization’s affiliate CEMEC (Centre European pour la Medecin des Catastrophes) in Italy. He was elected a Fellow of the American College of Physicians in 1997 and a Fellow of the Explorer’s Club in 2014.\n\n

Rasmussen is a Research Professor in Environmental Security and Global Medicine at San Diego State University and an instructor in disaster medicine at both the International Disaster Academy in Bonn, Germany (BBK, or Bundesamt für Bevölkerungsschutz ind Katastrophenhilfe) and the Institute for Disaster Preparedness at Tsinghua University in Beijing, China.\n\n

He is a member of the core faculty at Singularity University within the NASA Ames Research Center, teaching in both the Exponential Medicine and Global Grand Challenges tracks. He also serves as Permanent Advisor to the UN Secretary-General’s High Level Expert Panel on Water Disasters, and is a member of the US National Academy of Science’s Committee on Grand Challenges in Global Development.\n\n

Rasmussen served as a physician in the US Navy for 25 years aboard nuclear submarines, amphibious ships and aircraft carriers. He was Fleet Surgeon for the US Navy’s Third Fleet and chairman of an academic department of medicine in Seattle. Among his wartime deployments are Bosnia (x3), Afghanistan (x2), and Iraq for ten months. His disaster deployments include Supertyphoon Haiyan in the Philippines, Haiti’s earthquake, Banda Aceh for the tsunami, Superstorm Sandy in New York, and New Orleans after Hurricane Katrina.\n\n

He also spent nine years as a Principal Investigator in humanitarian informatics for the Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency (DARPA) and received DARPA’s capstone award as Outstanding Investigator of the Year before retiring from the Navy to serve as the CEO of InSTEDD, a humanitarian NGO established by Dr. Larry Brilliant, then Executive Director of Google.org. InSTEDD’s charter is to put into action the goals outlined by Dr. Brilliant’s TED Prize speech for better global disease outbreak surveillance and response. Dr. Rasmussen shifted from CEO to Chair of the InSTEDD Board in 2010 and became CEO of IHS soon after.\n\n

IHS is particularly good at the provisioning of clean drinking water in very difficult settings using ceramic nanotechnologies for renewable-powered, robust, efficient, portable, and inexpensive water reclamation and purification systems. IHS also currently manages the Global Disaster Response Team for the Roddenberry Foundation, supported by the Star Trek franchise.\n\n

Eric lives with Demi, his wife of 30 years, on Bainbridge Island near Seattle, Washington. They have two excellent daughters, one doing biochemistry in Seattle, one doing permaculture in Canada.</string>
    <string name="sarpong_bio">Richmond Sarpong, who was born in Ghana, West Africa, is a professor of chemistry in the Department of Chemistry at the University of California, Berkeley, where he has been since 2004. He moved to the United States in 1991 after a childhood and adolescent years in Ghana, Zambia, and Botswana, respectively.\n\n

He was an undergraduate student at Macalester College, obtained his Ph.D. from Princeton University, and conducted a postdoctoral stay at Caltech.\n\n

Richmond and his research group at Berkeley are interested in identifying efficient and versatile ways to prepare natural products, which are compounds isolated from living organisms that form the basis for over 50percent of the medicines that are currently on the market. His passion to pursue science with potential medicinal value was driven by the scourge of river blindness and AIDS in sub-Saharan Africa, which he witnessed first hand.\n\n

Richmond has served the chemistry community in many capacities. He is a member of the National Institutes of Health study section that evaluates proposals in the area of chemical synthesis and is on the board of editors for Organic Syntheses, a journal that provides robust chemical procedures. He is the recipient of numerous awards including the Alfred P. Sloan Fellowship, the Camille Dreyfus Teacher-Scholar award, a Cope Scholar Award from the American Chemical Society, and a teaching award from the Department of Chemistry at UC Berkeley in 2009.</string>
    <string name="robins_bio">Mike Robbins is the author of three books, Focus on the Good Stuff, Be Yourself Everyone Else is Already Taken, and his latest, Nothing Changes Until You Do.  Mike travels throughout the country and the world sharing his stories, insights, and ideas with clients like Google, Citibank, Microsoft, Schwab, eBay, Kaiser, and the San Francisco Giants.  Mike and his work have been featured in Forbes and Fast Company, as well as on ABC News and the Oprah radio network.  He’s a regular contributor to the Huffington Post and his books have been translated into 14 different languages.  For more information about Mike and his work, feel free to visit

</string>
    <string name="meyer_bio">Alison teaches leadership communications at UC Berkeley’s Haas School of Business and around the world. She also consults to individuals and corporations as an executive coach, facilitator, and leadership program developer. A proud UC Berkeley “double bear” (MBA 2011, BA Art History 1987) she helps people find their stories and voice, move through giant obstacles, be curious about the people around them, listen fiercely, open their hearts, and aspire outrageously. Her company is www.UnconditionalLeadership.com.\n\n

During her 20s she worked various administrative roles in art, design and consulting companies, and started to train and perform in theater at night. Building skill in accounting led to consultancy with clients in design, tech and manufacturing. The business afforded flexibility for her passion, theater, while she built a practice as a trusted advisor to entrepreneurial, innovative clients. The next 10 years were business consultant by day, singer-actress by night, and not much sleep.\n\n

In 2005, after much soul-searching, she closed the consulting business and put aside singing to find focus on a single career combining left brain and right brain, arts, technology and business. This intention led her to Apple’s iTunes, where she helped build the digital content business in TV and Movies.\n\n

During the Apple years, life stabilized, she watched a lot of TV, and immersed herself in tech. She returned to Berkeley for the #1-ranked Haas Evening Weekend MBA, and was promoted to Manager at Apple.\n\n

At Haas Alison discovered that the experience she’d left behind in the acting studio and on stage could be used in the real world to help people develop their presence and find their voice. In 2009 she began teaching leadership communications at Haas, and consulting to companies and private clients. In 2013 she transitioned into coaching and consulting full time.\n\n

The coaching process and mindset has taught her life-changing skills around slowing down, really listening, stepping into difficulty bravely, and making others look good, skills that she already had from theater. Her mission is to pass these tools on, and teach others how to pass them on. Her current favorite word is “yet.”</string>
    <string name="sheenoy_bio">Skilled  in skilling.  Abling  the disabled.\n\n

It is inspirational to help the poor. Or the  disabled.  Or  the young in remote villages of rural India.   Meera  Shenoy has transformed lives in  all three categories. She has pioneered a training model that skills   underprivileged youth for jobs in today’s market. She has achieved this, while in leadership positions in the government, the private sector, and presently, in a social enterprise.\n\n

Meera  Shenoy  is the Founder-Chairperson of Youth4Jobs (www.youth4jobs.org), which focuses on helping companies build an inclusive workforce. In just three years,  Y4J has become one of the largest organisations in India in the field. It has  reached out to over 100,000 rural households, trained 4500 disabled youth, and placed  70 percent in jobs, and 40 percent of these are girls with disabilities.\n\n

Meera was awarded the NCPEDP-Shell Helen Keller award in 2012. Her disability work was featured online in the Harvard Business Review and the Stanford Social Innovation Review.\n\n

In 2004,  Meera was asked to join the Andhra Pradesh government to initiate and lead India’s first Jobs Mission for rural and tribal youth. She changed the focus of the government’s work from ‘training for training’s sake’, to  market-linked training programs for youth, including  the last mile of placing them in jobs. Meera Shenoy has uniquely shown, that large-scale job training and placement can be done, and in a short period.  When she left in 2010, the Jobs Mission had become one of the largest jobs mission for the poor, with 150,000 rural and tribal youth placed in jobs, over  5 years. Scale in hirings came from training innovations tailored to market needs, such as creating India’s first grass-roots program in  English, work readiness and computer skills. A unique IT architecture linked to e-payment ensured transparency.\n\n

The Jobs Mission work won several awards including the South Asia Manthan award for e-inclusion. It was featured in Knowledge@Wharton and the Wall Street Journal.\n\n

Meera  was commissioned by the ILO to do their India country strategy, for persons with disability and labour markets. From 2012-14 she was Senior Advisor, UNDP, for youth skilling and employment. She also supported the office of the Chairman, National Skill Development Agency, the highest policy making body in India in this field. For the past seven years she has also worked as a World Bank consultant in youth and skilling, in their poverty alleviation projects  across South Asia.</string>
    <string name="svitak_bio">Since the age of four, Adora has been exploring what she can do with the written word: everything from championing literacy and youth voice to working with the UN’s World Food Programme to raise awareness about world hunger. Hoping to instill her love of writing in others, she taught her first class at a local elementary school the year her first book, Flying Fingers, debuted; since then, she has spoken at hundreds of schools, classrooms and conferences around the world. In 2010, she delivered the speech “What Adults Can Learn from Kids” at TED. The speech received over 3.3 million views on TED.com alone, and has been translated into over 40 different languages. That same year, Adora started organizing TEDxRedmond, a youth conference attracting over 700 attendees each year. Over the course of years of speaking, her audiences have included teachers, CEOs, entrepreneurs, artists, students, and delegates at the United Nations Economic and Social Council’s Youth Forum.\n\n

Pacific Standard Magazine described Adora as one of the “30 Top Thinkers Under 30,” going on to call her “an activist for feminism, liberal politics, and youth-oriented causes […] pretty far up the road to becoming intellectual royalty.” She has written widely, including pieces for Mashable, the Huffington Post, and Berkeley Political Review as well as contributions to poetry anthologies. Excerpts from her speeches and blog posts have been included in writing textbooks around the world. She is a 2011 recipient of the National Education Association Foundation’s Award for Outstanding Service to Public Education, an honor previously bestowed on luminaries ranging from Bill Clinton to Billie Jean King. Adora is currently a freshman at UC Berkeley, where she is majoring in Political Science.</string>
    <string name="octet_bio">The UC Men’s Octet is an eight member a cappella singing group comprised of some of the finest male singers at the University of California, Berkeley. Founded in 1948, the Octet has entertained audiences around the world with its unique mesh of close harmonies and zany stage antics as well as with a wide repertoire of barbershop, doo-wop, contemporary pop, modern alternative, and of course, Cal fight songs, the group has released dozens of recordings over the years. That being said, their most important performances are held on Sproul Plaza each Wednesday at one o’clock in front of our greatest fans, the Cal students. We’re super exited to be performing at TEDxBerkeley this year and hope you enjoy!</string>
    <string name="taiko_bio">In the Spring of 2005, a small-but-committed group of students pooled together their resources and formed UC Berkeley’s first taiko group. Since then, Cal Raijin Taiko has gone on to become Berkeley’s premier Japanese drumming performance ensemble. With a repertoire consisting entirely of original compositions, Cal Raijin Taiko performs to spread the knowledge, love, and passion of taiko to both the campus and the surrounding communities. In the decade since it’s inception, the members of Cal Raijin Taiko have composed over a dozen unique and vibrant songs, and performed for scores of audiences large and small. Our alumni have spread throughout the country, many of them founding entirely new taiko groups in the cities where they settle. Every Fall we accept new members to make up the next Generation of our Cal Raijin Taiko family.
</string>
    <string name="viederman_bio">As CEO of Verité, Dan Viederman has worked closely with NGOs, governments, investors, and the biggest multinational brands in the world to improve working conditions and eliminate human rights violations across geographies and business sectors. For the impact that Verité has had on the millions of workers around the world, Viederman was the winner of a 2007 Skoll Foundation Award for Social Entrepreneurship, and was named 2011 Social Entrepreneur of the Year in the United States by the Geneva, Switzerland-based Schwab Foundation for Social Entrepreneurship. Dan has managed NGOs in developing countries since 1993 and worked with internationally-recognized institutions such as the World Wildlife Fund (WWF) and Catholic Relief Services. He has lived extensively in Asia and speaks Chinese. Dan is a graduate of Yale University, the Columbia University School of International and Public Affairs, and Nanjing Teacher’s University.</string>

    <string name="woz_bio">A Silicon Valley icon and philanthropist for more than thirty years, Steve Wozniak has helped shape the computing industry with his design of Apple’s first line of products the Apple I and II and influenced the popular Macintosh. In 1976, Wozniak and Steve Jobs founded Apple Computer Inc. with Wozniak’s Apple I personal computer. The following year, he introduced his Apple II personal computer, featuring a central processing unit, a keyboard, color graphics, and a floppy disk drive. The Apple II was integral in launching the personal computer industry.\n\n

In 1981, he went back to UC Berkeley and finished his degree in electrical engineering/computer science. For his achievements at Apple, Wozniak was awarded the National Medal of Technology by the President of the United States in 1985, the highest honor bestowed on America’s leading innovators.\n\n

In 2000, he was inducted into the Inventors Hall of Fame and was awarded the prestigious Heinz Award for Technology, The Economy and Employment for single-handedly designing the first personal computer and for then redirecting his lifelong passion for mathematics and electronics toward lighting the fires of excitement for education in grade school students and their teachers.\n\n

Through the years, Wozniak has been involved in various business and philanthropic ventures, focusing primarily on computer capabilities in schools and stressing hands-on learning and encouraging creativity for students.  Making significant investments of both his time and resources in education, he adopted the Los Gatos School District, providing students and teachers with hands-on teaching and donations of state-of-the-art technology equipment. He founded the Electronic Frontier Foundation, and was the founding sponsor of the Tech Museum, Silicon Valley Ballet and Children’s Discovery Museum of San Jose.\n\n

Wozniak is Chief Scientist at Primary Data and is a published author with the release of his New York Times best selling autobiography, iWoz: From Computer Geek to Cult Icon by Norton Publishing. His television appearances include reality shows Kathy Griffin: My Life on the D-List, ABC’s Dancing with the Stars and The Big Bang Theory.  In 2014, he was awarded the Hoover Medal, a prestigious honor given for “outstanding extra-career services by engineers to humanity,” and was inducted into the IndustryWeek Manufacturing Hall of Fame.</string>

</resources>
