<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">TEDxBerkeley</string>
    <string name="hello_world">Hello world!</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="about">About</string>
    <string name="speakers">Speakers</string>
    <string name="schedule">Schedule</string>
    <string name="navigation_icon_description">TEDxBerkeley Logo</string>
    <string name="speaker_photo">Speaker Photo</string>
    <string name="talk_icon">Talk Icon</string>

    <string name="about_ted">
        TED is a nonprofit organization devoted to Ideas Worth Spreading. Started as a four-day conference in California 25 years ago, TED has grown to support those world-changing ideas with multiple initiatives. The annual TED Conference invites the world’s leading thinkers and doers to speak for 18 minutes. Their talks are then made available, free, at TED.com.\n\nTED speakers have included Bill Gates, Al Gore, Jane Goodall, Elizabeth Gilbert, Sir Richard Branson, Nandan Nilekani, Philippe Starck, Ngozi Okonjo-Iweala, Isabel Allende and former UK Prime Minister Gordon Brown. The annual TED Conference takes place each spring in Long Beach, California, along with the TEDActive simulcast in Palm Springs; the annual TEDGlobal conference is held each summer in Edinburgh, Scotland. \n\n

        TED’s media initiatives include TED.com, where new TEDTalks are posted daily, the recently launched TED-Ed platform for students and educators, the Open Translation Project, which provides subtitles and interactive transcripts as well as the ability for any TEDTalk to be translated by volunteers worldwide, and TEDBooks, short e-books by speakers that elaborate on a single idea originally presented on TED’s stage. \n\nTED has established the annual TED Prize, where exceptional individuals with a wish to change the world are given the opportunity to put their wishes into action; TEDx, which offers individuals or groups a way to host local, self-organized events around the world, and the TED Fellows program, helping world-changing innovators from around the globe to become part of the TED community and, with its help, amplify the impact of their remarkable projects and activities.</string>

    <string name="about_tedxberkeley">  On February 6, 2016 TEDxBerkeley is gathering world-leading thinkers, makers, and doers at UC Berkeley to discuss “Finding x.” The audience will be composed of a diverse mix of over 2000 students, professors, and thought leaders from Berkeley and beyond for a stimulating day of presentations, discussions, entertainment and art that will spark new ideas and opportunities for all.  \n</string>

    <string name="lorem_ispum">Bacon ipsum dolor amet pork loin prosciutto flank beef ribs kielbasa tongue. Jerky capicola chuck, corned beef ball tip meatloaf porchetta rump tongue shoulder turkey cow. Tail prosciutto spare ribs pancetta beef ribs, rump sausage landjaeger t-bone ball tip filet mignon meatball bresaola. Hamburger biltong swine cupim meatloaf tongue frankfurter kielbasa chicken. Meatball drumstick biltong salami, shank ball tip kielbasa capicola. Chuck ball tip prosciutto bacon boudin doner capicola landjaeger ham chicken t-bone tongue ribeye turducken alcatra. Shoulder beef ribs fatback cupim pork chop filet mignon bresaola porchetta cow short loin pancetta pig sirloin.

Prosciutto landjaeger spare ribs turkey tenderloin tongue kevin meatball beef ribs shank. Beef pastrami shank meatball doner cupim bresaola ball tip jowl turkey rump strip steak hamburger leberkas ham. Jerky boudin jowl t-bone. Filet mignon venison meatloaf, t-bone shoulder beef ribs tongue doner shank turducken brisket meatball pig. Meatball landjaeger ribeye chicken tenderloin turducken, shankle shoulder.

Filet mignon corned beef tongue short ribs meatball cow tri-tip drumstick pork belly doner beef ribs meatloaf prosciutto. Ham pork chop short ribs tail chuck bresaola. Meatloaf pork sirloin shankle. Bacon brisket shoulder, swine tri-tip picanha prosciutto turkey chuck beef ribs andouille shank filet mignon. Frankfurter turducken shank tri-tip meatloaf kielbasa.

Cupim flank meatloaf tongue boudin filet mignon andouille ground round swine frankfurter sausage. Frankfurter meatball cow picanha landjaeger filet mignon beef ribs salami swine boudin doner brisket. Jowl drumstick beef ribs short loin landjaeger turkey, pastrami beef capicola swine porchetta corned beef t-bone pork belly jerky. Salami corned beef biltong ham.

Strip steak meatball beef ribs bresaola kevin alcatra salami pork picanha. Landjaeger rump flank pork chuck shankle cow meatloaf sausage shoulder short ribs tongue. Tail pork spare ribs sausage cupim tongue drumstick. Brisket porchetta chicken pork belly corned beef chuck doner. Landjaeger tenderloin leberkas andouille, kevin corned beef tongue bacon ham rump turducken tail meatloaf turkey. Cow jerky brisket boudin turkey.</string>

    <string name="ategeka_bio"> Christopher Ategeka is award-winning social entrepreneur, engineer, and inventor. Among his many inventions is the patent of nanotechnology that can detect and monitor chronic diseases. Ategeka previously served as the founder and CEO of Ride for Lives, a company that builds innovative vehicles to deliver healthcare services in developing countries. He has been recognized in publications such as NPR and BBC for his work as a social entrepreneur. Additionally, Ategeka was included in the 2014 “Forbes 30 Under 30” list. Ategeka is a University of California, Berkeley alumnus, holding a Bachelor of Science and Master of Science in Mechanical Engineering.
 </string>
    <string name="calvin_bio"> Kathy Calvin is the President and CEO of the United Nations Foundation. Calvin diverse career, spanning the public, private, and nonprofit sectors, has fueled her passion for multi-sector problem solving. At the United Nations Foundation, Calvin connects people, resources, and ideas in order to advocate for the United Nation’s causes and activities. The United Nation Foundation’s work focuses on decreasing child mortality, empowering women and girls, creating a clean energy future, using mobile technology for development, and improving U.S.-UN relations. Calvin’s philanthropy and leadership have been featured in the New York Times. She was also named one of Newsweek’s “150 Women Who Rock the World.”
 </string>
    <string name="corn_bio"> Jacob Corn is the Scientific Director of the Innovative Genomics Initiative and a University of California, Berkeley faculty member in the department of Molecular and Cell Biology. Corn previously worked at Genentech in the department of Early Discovery Biochemistry, interrogating the feasibility for challenging therapeutic pathways in neurobiology, infectious disease, and oncology. Corn’s current research investigates how biophysical properties interact within the cellular environment to shape signaling behavior, and how disease arises when these properties go awry. At the Innovative Genomics Initiative, Corn seeks to push the boundaries of genome editing in order to improve insight into fundamental biology, and to lay the groundwork for clinical and commercial applications.
 </string>
    <string name="freid_bio"> Stephanie Freid is a television correspondent for China Central Television (CCTV) and Turkish Television International networks. She formerly was a freelance producer for programs including BBC and NBC News. Freid reports from the world’s conflict zones. Her assignments have covered the current refugee crisis, the Israeli-Palestinian Conflict, and Ebola outbreak in West Africa. Furthermore, she has reported on the wars in Syria, Ukraine, Libya, Iraq, and Mali. Freid views her work as a privilege, as her close proximity to conflict provides glimpses of humankind’s ugliest and most incredible traits.
    </string>

    <string name="hotchkiss_bio"> Rob Hotchkiss won a Grammy Award (Best Rock Song) for five-time nominated “Drops of Jupiter”, and was the musical force behind hits such as Meet Virginia, Free, I Am , and Get To Me. Rob founded the band, Train, and his songwriting was integral to their multi-platinum success. For creative reasons Rob left Train after their third album to record and produce the solo album, Midnight Ghost, which received tremendous critical acclaim. Rob’s classic sound, with meaningful lyrics, beautiful melodies, and lush harmonies, has been likened to The Beatles, Neil Young, and more current artists like Ed Sheeran. After several years of retirement from music, Rob moved back to the Bay Area to work with Tom Luce (of LUCE) and Charlie Colin (former member of Train) on a project called Painbirds, releasing an eponymous EP in June of 2015. Rob is currently performing as a solo artist, writing songs and performing in the Bay Area and Los Angeles, with plans to tour the West Coast.
 </string>
    <string name="jain_bio"> Naveen Jain is an entrepreneur and philanthropist driven to solve the world’s challenges using innovation. Jain is a founder of many businesses, including InfoSpace, Intelius, and iNome. His latest project is Moon Express, a company dedicated to developing a robotic lunar lander mine the moon for natural resources. Moreover, Jain is a trustee of the board for the X Prize Foundation, a public competition in search for solutions to global challenges in health, education, poverty, agriculture, and clean water. Jain’s leadership and entrepreneurial spirit have earned him many awards, including “Ernst and Young Entrepreneur of the Year” and Silicon India’s “Most Admired Serial Entrepreneur.”
 </string>
    <string name="johnson_bio"> Jeromy Johnson is an expert in mitigating the negative impacts of Electromagnetic Field (EMF) exposure. Jeromy has an advanced degree in Civil Engineering and has worked in Silicon Valley for 15 years. After becoming what medical doctors call “Electro-hypersensitive” (EHS) in 2011 due to extensive exposure to EMF radiation, Jeromy immersed himself in the available data on the impacts of EMF exposure. His experience and knowledge inspire us to create new technologies and to utilize existing technologies in ways that are safer for humans, animals and the environment.
 </string>
    <string name="deborah_bio"> Deborah Johnson is a voice for compassion, justice, and reconciliation. She is the founder and president of The Motivational Institute, an organizational development consulting firm specializing in diversity, and Inner Light Ministries, which teaches practical applications of Universal Spiritual Principles. She holds a vision of Oneness, beyond creed and doctrine, and builds bridges between those adhering to conservative and progressive ideologies. The ground breaking work of Deborah Johnson has received many awards and been featured in numerous books, magazines, and television programs including appearances on The Donahue Show, ABC Nightline, Showtime, Glamour and Ms. Magazines, Shambhala Sun, and NPR.
 </string>
    <string name="celli_bio"> Celli@Berkeley was created one night in 2012 after the cellists of the UC Berkeley Symphony Orchestra realized that the only thing better than one cello was many, many cellos. Composed of sixteen students studying a variety of academic disciplines, they are united by a desire to express the possibilities of the cello. They love performing and sharing music ranging from classical to pop, not only in concert halls but also outdoors - by the Campanile, in art galleries, at marathons or flea markets, and on the streets of Berkeley!
 </string>
    <string name="khanna_bio"> Aran Khanna is a student-developer, blogger, and student at Harvard who is working to understand the consequences of the increasing role of technology in our lives, particularly in the realm of personal privacy. Aran builds tools that empower users to discover for themselves the consequences of the digital footprint they are leaving. Notably Aran’s work on disclosing the dangers of default location sharing in Facebook Messenger spurred Facebook to remove the feature from Messenger. It also prompted Facebook to rescind Aran’s internship offer, raising questions about how social media companies respond to privacy issues.
 </string>
    <string name="koenig_bio"> John Koenig has spent the last decade building a home in every creative field he can find, working as a graphic designer, video editor, voice actor, illustrator, photographer, director, and writer. He has spent the last six years writing an original dictionary of made-up words, The Dictionary of Obscure Sorrows, which fills gaps in the language with hundreds of new terms for emotions, some of which (‘sonder’) have entered the language outright. Business Standard has said “Koenig is a writer to be reckoned with” and stated “The Dictionary is the kind of thing you want to print and bind, and refer to often.”
 </string>
    <string name="leanse_bio"> Ellen Petry Leanse is a digital pioneer and road-tested entrepreneur who Ellen has guided entrepreneurs and policy makers in East Africa, India, Italy, Latin America, Asia, and in the U.S. on innovation and strategy. As a digital pioneer and road-tested entrepreneur, Ellen has guided more than 40 technology companies spanning early stage to global leaders including Microsoft, Facebook, Samsung, Intuit, Oracle, and Women 2.0. Additionally, Ellen writes and speaks on innovation, gender, and ethics and is a member of Stanford’s Continuing Education faculty, teaching “Enlightened Innovation” as part of the extended studies curriculum.
 </string>
    <string name="lim_bio"> Dr Susan Lim’s historic performance of the first successful cadaveric liver transplant for Singapore and Asia in 1990 propelled her into the media spotlight at the age of 35. She became the first in Asia, and the second woman in the world to have performed a successful liver transplant at that time. She holds many academic recognitions and honors, and even has an award for continuing medical education named after her for her work in the advancement of Laparoscopic and Minimally Invasive Surgery. Her desire to discover that next big thing keeps her actively focused on robotics and stem cell research. She strongly believes that as society increasingly embraces technology, communication and interactions will extend beyond humans to robots and other inanimates.
 </string>
    <string name="choir_bio"> The Oakland School of the Arts (OSA) Chamber Choir is the largest audition-only high school Vocal ensemble at OSA. They have performed at notable events including President Obama\'s 2012 campaign tour and the Giants Game at AT&amp;T park, and with celebrities including Sean Penn, Robert Downey Jr., and the band CAKE. In addition,the students have traveled to New Orleans, Italy and Puerto Rico for concert tours. The OSA Chamber Choir is directed by Ms. Cava Menzies.
 </string>
    <string name="rao_bio"> On the surface, Sonia Rao is a pop singer/songwriter with over 35 film and television placements and a BMI Spotlight Artist. Her songs have been featured on MTV’s Jersey Shore, ABC’s The Vineyard, Keeping Up With the Kardashians, and many others. But dig into Sonia’s music and you’ll discover she’s an vessel of inspiration. At a recent TEDxWomen event, she was asked to perform and speak about gender equality, just one of the issues she holds dear. Sonia captivated the room with her energy, and it’s with that same spirit that she welcomes us into her world on her forthcoming album, Meet Them At The Door, her most transparent work yet.
</string>
    <string name="ray_bio"> Isha Ray is Associate Professor at the Energy and Resources Group and Co-Director (with Professor David Sedlak) of the Berkeley Water Center. She has a BA in Philosophy, Politics and Economics from Oxford University, and a PhD in Applied Economics from the Food Research Institute at Stanford University. Her research projects focus on access to water and sanitation for the rural and urban poor, and on the role of technology in advancing sustainable development goals and improving livelihoods. She has worked on developing access to water in India, China, Turkey, Mexico, Tanzania and California’s Central Valley. Dr. Ray has extensive experience in the international non-profit sector on development and freshwater issues, and is a regular adviser to United Nations Women.
 </string>
    <string name="roche_bio"> Amandine Roche is a Human Rights expert who has worked with the United Nations, UNICEF, UNDP, UNESCO, and UN WOMEN for over 15 years. Her focus is on civic education, democratization, and gender and youth empowerment. After the kidnapping and assassination of her colleagues, Amandine was evacuated from Kabul, Afganistan. She found her inner peace in India and realized that non-violence was also the only way to achieve harmony for Afghanistan and the whole world. She returned to Kabul to create the Amanuddin Foundation in order to promote a culture of peace and non-violence.
 </string>
    <string name="shamasunder_bio"> Sriram Shamasunder completed his residency in Internal Medicine at Harbor UCLA Medical Center and is currently an Academic Hospitalist at UCSF. Sri has spent the last 10 years working several months a year in Burundi, Haiti, Rwanda and India. He is co-founder of the HEAL initiative, which aims to support workforce capacity in limited resource settings, both in the United States and internationally. In 2010, he received the Young Physician of the Year award from the Northern California Chapter of the American College of Physicians. He is interested in health equity and narrative equity, working towards a world where lives are of equal value both the health care we deliver and the stories we highlight.
 </string>
    <string name="siemion_bio"> Dr. Andrew Siemion is an astrophysicist at the University of California (UC), Berkeley and serves as Director of the UC Berkeley Center for Search for Extraterrestrial Intelligence (SETI) Research. His research interests include studies of time-variable celestial phenomena, astronomical instrumentation and SETI. Dr. Siemion is one of the leaders of the “Breakthrough Listen Initiative” – a 10 year, 100 million dollar effort, sponsored by Yuri Milner’s Breakthrough Prize Foundation, that is conducting the most sensitive search for advanced extraterrestrial life in history, and has received many awards for his work on searches for exotic radio phenomena. Dr. Siemion frequently appears on international television and radio discussing the search for life beyond on Earth and the prospects for detection.
 </string>
    <string name="toch_bio"> UC Berkeley sophomore Joshua Toch plans to pursue a degree in Business Administration with a minor in Industrial engineering. At the age of 15, he took a stance against bullying by speaking about his personal experiences with Cerebral Palsy. He founded Mind Before Mouth, a not-for-profit organization that visits schools and clubs to encourage teamwork to get through hardship. Toch is the recipient of the 2014 Morgan Hill Chamber of Commerce Student of the Year and the 2014 Diller Teen Tikkun Olam Award. He has spoken at TEDxUCDavisSF and will be a part of Patricia Wooster’s upcoming book, “So You Want to Be A Leader?” in 2016.
</string>
    <string name="azaad_bio"> UCB Azaad, referring to “independence or freedom”, is excited to bring a fresh, new taste of Bollywood to Berkeley! The team is based on dedication, passion and energy, with the primary goal of creating productions that entertain and motivate audiences to connect with the Bollywood culture.
 </string>

</resources>

